Abram Shook - Austin, Texas | 617-686-4263 | shookstack.atx@gmail.com

LinkedIn | Gitlab

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Over 20 years of experience in multiple industries including tech, hospitality, training and music, with an eagerness to learn new skill sets and a focus on continuous improvement. Currently enjoying a career in software engineering at the intersection of creativity and programming. Adaptable problem solver with a calm, purposeful work ethic.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

DEVELOPER: JavaScript - React - TypeScript - Next.js - Node.js - Ruby - Rails - AWS - HTML - CSS - Docker - Git - OpenSearch - SQL - GraphQL - Express

EXPERIENCE

Boater's List Remote
Lead Developer 3/2023 - present

• Managed successful upgrade of framework and dependencies for increased optimization

- Implemented complete UI overhaul employing modern tools leading to 134% increase in daily users
- Performed an AWS audit to identify budget bloat and decrease monthly expenditures by 18%
- Built multiple complex features on our booking platform including a Voucherify integration that allows businesses to run custom discount/coupon campaigns
- Identified pinch-points in our search queries and improved data retrieval by organizing and remapping our OpenSearch Indexes

PushgigRemoteSoftware Engineer5/2022 - 3/2023

- General coding and development
- Data aggregation and management for music-related sites
- Error handling, testing, and bug fixes

 Accenture
 Remote

 SME/QA
 11/2020 - 04/2022

- Pinpointed areas of improvement and implemented new guidelines to adhere to metrics and compliance regulations
- Maintained and updated knowledge-base articles in accordance with technical specifications
- Kept meticulous documentation when investigating new bugs in order to communicate efficiently with the development team on possible new bugs or trends that impacted the application

Hai Hospitality Austin, TX

Trainer/Opening Captain

02/2006 -10/2018

Lead a team of 40+ employees through trainings and standards of service with one-on-one reviews and mentorship

EDUCATION

AWS Cloud Practitioner Austin, TX

Completed Amazon's certification program for AWS cloud fundamentals

Flatiron School Austin, TX

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program

Cabrillo College Santa Cruz, CA

music performance